unimaas.nl 2018-08-29

# UM General Privacy Statement

UM General Privacy Statement
Introduction
Your privacy is important to Maastricht University (UM) and UM therefore treats your data with
care. UM is the controller of your personal data. This privacy statement explains how UM handles
personal data.
Your personal data may be collected and processed for a specific purpose. If this specific purpose is
not expressly specified in this privacy statement, you will be informed in advance about this
specific purpose in a separate privacy statement.
Contact details
If you have a query about this privacy statement or you want to know more about how UM handles
personal data, or if you have a complaint, please contact:
Maastricht University
attn. Data Protection Officer
Postbus 616
6200 MD Maastricht
privacy@maastrichtuniversity.nl
You can also contact UM’s Data Protection Officer directly by emailing fg@maastrichtuniversity.nl.
What personal data does UM process?
UM always has a purpose for processes personal data, and does not process more data than is
necessary for that purpose. A general overview of these purposes can be found further on in this
privacy statement.
UM receives personal data directly from you or from a third party that is authorised or required to
share this personal data with UM.
An overview of the categories of (special) personal data that UM may process is set out below:
Category of personal data                          Examples
Name and address details                           name, address, postal code, town/city
Age-related data                                   age and date of birth
Contact details                                    email address(es) and telephone number(s)
Gender
Nationality                                        Second/third nationality, place of birth
Education and professional experience              CV, certificates, diplomas
Financial data                                     IBAN, credit card details, salary, income,
                                                   statements of expenses.
Identification data                                BSN number, ID document number, passport
                                                   photo
Student file-related data                          Academic       progress,     marks,      completed
                                                   education, degree programme, assessments,
                                                   matching, student ID, binding study advice,
                                                   incident record, allocations from funds (e.g.
                                                   student assistance fund).
Alumni-related data                                Email address, telephone number, address for
                                                   correspondence,         nationality,      language
                                                   preference,      academic       details,     career
                                                   information, information on interaction with UM
                                                   (e.g. participation in events), details of
                                                   relationship status, subscription to newsletters,

                                                    alumni circle institutions, personal data shared
                                                    for     a   specific   purpose     (e.g.   dietary
                                                    requirements), financial information relating to
                                                    sponsorship.
Account data                                        Login details, social media accounts, IP
                                                    addresses.
Location data                                       Logging data, IP address, building access data.
Usage data for UM facilities                        Logging data, IP address, location data.
Biometric data                                      Passport photo
Photos and video images                             Visual materials, promotional materials, camera
                                                    images.
Medical data                                        Data relating to illness and absence, data
                                                    relating to physical or mental disabilities,
                                                    special circumstances in the context of study
                                                    delay.
Academic research                                   Data (created) in the context of academic
                                                    research.
Sensitive personal data are data that are special in nature. For example, these can be data that
reveal your race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union
membership or sexual orientation. The term sensitive personal data also includes data about your
health, genetic data or biometric data through which you can be identified (e.g. a fingerprint). UM
only processes sensitive data when it is permitted to do so by law.
Purposes
UM processes personal data for the following purposes:
   educational activities;
   alumni activities;
   academic research;
   operational management.
Education
In the context of its educational activities, UM processes the personal data of (prospective)
students for the following purposes:
   to establish the identity of students and potential students;
   to inform potential students about UM’s degree programmes;
   to recruit new students and to promote UM;
   to perform matching;
   to perform administrative proceedings relating to applications, enrolment/registration and
    termination of enrolment/registration, and to calculate, record and collect tuition and exam
    fees;
   to assess previous education and to manage draws, matching and selection;
   to register students for courses and examinations and to record attendance;
   to offer and provide educational resources, IT facilities and catering facilities;
   to support students with a disability;
   to measure and improve the quality of education and educational facilities;
   to prepare policy decisions in the field of education and to create management information for
    UM’s management bodies;
   to offer additional education, work placements, career preparation and other extracurricular
    activities;
   to organise and hold university elections;
   to record academic results, test and examination results and to award degree certificates;
   to advise and support students and to assess special circumstances in the context of a binding
    study advice;
   to advise on and process complaints, objections and appeals;
   to comply with the statutory duty to retain alumni degree certificates;

   to keep the university’s buildings secure;
   to keep information and IT facilities secure and to ensure that they function effectively.
Alumni activities
In the context of alumni activities, UM processes the personal data of alumni for the following
purposes:
   to obtain funds from alumni;
   to maintain digital and other contact with alumni;
   to conduct research into and amongst alumni;
   to offer services to alumni.
Research
UM may process your personal data in the context of academic research. UM does this in the public
interest, in the interests of UM’s partners and/or in the legitimate interests of UM itself. You will
always be specifically informed about this and, where necessary and required by law, will be asked
for your consent.
Operational management
In the context of its operations, UM processes personal data for the following purposes:
   to prepare policy decisions in the field of operations and to create management information for
    UM’s management bodies;
   to organise and hold university elections;
   to process complaints, objections and appeals and to deal with other legal matters;
   to keep financial records and to draw up and approve annual accounts and budgets;
   to draw up UM’s annual reports;
   to complete accreditation and certification processes;
   to offer and provide products and services;
   to purchase products and services and to manage contracts;
   to secure, maintain and run the university’s buildings;
   to secure information and ensure the proper functioning of IT facilities;
   to inform the contacts of students and staff in the event of an emergency;
   to keep a record of incidents and reports concerning (suspected) domestic violence and/or child
    abuse;
   to compile user statistics for UM’s facilities.
UMcard
The UMcard enables use of the facilities offered by UM and, where relevant, Maastricht academic
hospital (azM). Every student receives a UMcard on enrolment. The UMcard is used within UM as a
proof of identity. The UMcard can be used for the following purposes:
   access control (buildings and car parks);
   payments;
   library applications;
   identification;
   monitoring of UMcard abuse.
Camera surveillance
UM uses cameras for the following purposes:
   to protect the health and safety of staff, students and visitors to UM;
   to safeguard access to UM buildings and sites;
   to protect property present in UM buildings or on UM sites;
   to record incidents;
   to regulate traffic flows for students, staff and visitors to UM.
The camera images are kept for a maximum of four weeks. Where there are legitimate grounds for
doing so, camera images may be kept for longer. This may be the case if the camera images have
recorded an incident. In that case, the images will be kept for as long as is necessary for the

purposes of further investigation and any measures that may need to be taken, until such time as
the detected incident has been dealt with.
Newsletter
UM sends UM news and messages from the Executive Board to students by email on a weekly
basis. You cannot unsubscribe from these newsletters unless you are an alumnus.
UM also sends out other newsletters. You can subscribe to receive these newsletters. If you
subscribe to such a newsletter, you will receive it at the email address you have specified until such
time as you unsubscribe. This option is provided in the newsletters themselves.
UM Magazine
UM greatly values its partnerships. So, if you are partner of UM, UM will send you the UM Magazine
by post on a regular basis. You can unsubscribe to the UM Magazine at any time. To do so, please
email UM at magazine@maastrichtuniversity.nl or call +31 43 388 5222.
ICT facilities, including the (Wi-Fi) network
If you use UM’s ICT facilities, including the (Wi-Fi) network, personal data, such as the
identification number (MAC address) and technical characteristics of your device, your login code
and your IP address, are collected automatically. These data are only used to monitor the integrity
and security of the ICT facilities and to prevent abuse. It will be deleted after six months, unless a
longer retention period is necessary to deal with an incident. The conditions governing use of the
ICT facilities are set out in detail in the Acceptable Use Policy (AUP).
If you use ICT facilities for illegal activities or otherwise in contravention of the provisions of the
AUP, in addition to other measures, access by your device to UM’s network may be blocked.
UM’s website
Cookies
The UM website uses cookies. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer, mobile
phone or tablet when you consult pages on the UM website. The next time you visit the UM
website, the information stored in this cookie can be read by UM’s servers. Like virtually all
websites, the UM website uses cookies to offer you the best possible user experience when you
visit our website.
UM   uses cookies:
    so you only have to set specific preferences during and between visits to the UM website once;
    to make the website faster;
    so you can share certain pages via social media, such as Facebook and Twitter;
    to enable it to analyse website usage;
    to enable it to optimise the site and improve its contents.
You can learn more about the cookies that UM uses in UM’s Cookies Policy.
Secure connection
Whenever you visit the UM website, a secure connection is established between your device and
the UM website.
Lawful basis for the processing of personal data by UM
Whenever UM processes your personal data, it does so with a lawful basis for processing. A lawful
basis for processing is the grounds for processing personal data.
UM primarily processes your personal data to perform its public tasks in the field of the provision of
academic education and research. However, UM may also process your personal data:
    to perform a contract with you;
    to comply with a statutory obligation;

   to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of a third party;
   to serve the legitimate interests of UM or a third party;
   with your consent.
Further processing
The basic principle is that UM uses personal data for the purpose for which the data was collected.
In some cases, UM uses the personal data collected for other purposes too. These purposes must
always be compatible with the original purpose of processing. Before further processing takes
place, UM therefore carefully considers whether the new purpose is compatible with the original
purpose of processing.
According to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), further processing of personal data
for historical, statistical or scientific purposes is compatible with the original purpose of processing.
Retention periods
UM does not keep personal data for longer than is necessary to achieve the purpose of processing.
UM has defined a retention period for each type of processing. If this retention period can be
extended, the terms under which it may be extended are also specified.
In some cases, UM is subject to a statutory duty of retention. Pursuant to the Public Records Act
(Archiefwet), for example, UM is required to keep students’ degree certificates for 30 years.
Personal data can also be kept for a longer period for historical, statistical and scientific purposes.
If you would like to know the retention period for a specific type of processing, please contact UM
as follows:
Maastricht University
attn. Data Protection Officer
Postbus 616
6200 MD Maastricht
privacy@maastrichtuniversity.nl
You can also contact UM’s Data Protection Officer directly by emailing fg@maastrichtuniversity.nl.
Recipients of personal data
UM has taken steps to ensure that only those individuals who need to process your personal data
have access to it. In addition, UM may share data with parties outside of UM under the following
circumstances:
Third parties associated with UM
UM may share personal data with parties that are associated with or affiliated to UM, e.g. the
Limburg University Fund or Maastricht Academic Hospital. Where required by law, written contracts
concerning the processing and security of personal data have been concluded with these parties.
Government bodies
UM may share personal data with other government bodies where required to do so by law, e.g.
the Education Executive Agency (DUO). Personal data may also be shared with other government
bodies on the grounds of other compelling legitimate interests, e.g. the reporting of a theft or
assistance with an investigation.
Other educational institutions
UM may share your personal data with other educational institutions where this is necessary for the
provision of education jointly with that institution or for the performance of academic research in
conjunction with that institution. UM concludes written agreements with these parties concerning
the processing and security of personal data.

Third parties
UM shares data with third parties where this is necessary for the performance of its tasks, e.g.
suppliers of software that is used to process personal data or other service providers that need
personal data to provide their services. UM concludes written agreements with these parties
concerning the processing and security of personal data.
International processing
UM may share your personal data with a party outside of the European Union or an international
organisation. UM will ensure that your personal data are treated with care outside of the EU, and
that they are processed securely.
Some countries have been designated by the European Union as countries with an adequate level
of data protection. In other words, the statutory level of data protection is, at minimum, as high as
it is within the EU. In that case, UM does not need to take additional measures.
The EU has not designated the United States as a country with an adequate level of protection.
Parties may, however, subscribe to the EU-US Privacy Shield. Under this framework, they
demonstrate, through self-certification, that their level of data protection is adequate. In that case,
UM does not need to take additional measures.
If the level of protection in a country is regarded by the European Union as inadequate and the
relevant organisation has not subscribed to the EU-US Privacy Shield, UM will conclude an
agreement with the relevant party based on standard data protection provisions laid down by the
European Commission. To find out more about this, please contact UM as follows:
Maastricht University
attn. Data Protection Officer
Postbus 616
6200 MD Maastricht
privacy@maastrichtuniversity.nl
You can also contact UM’s Data Protection Officer directly by emailing fg@maastrichtuniversity.nl.
Your rights
Privacy legislation gives you a number of rights in relation to your personal data. Your rights, as
well as how to exercise them, are set out below.
Exercising your rights
If    you     wish   to    exercise   one   of   the    rights    described    below,    please     email
privacy@maastrichtuniversity.nl      or   contact    the    Data    Protection   Officer    directly  at
fg@maastrichtuniversity.nl.
UM will inform you, within a month of receiving your request, whether and, if so, how your request
will be dealt with. This time limit may be extended by one month on two occasions. If the time limit
is extended, you will be notified in good time that this is the case.
ID
In order to be sure that information is shared with the right person, UM may ask you for proof of
ID when you exercise your rights. If you are providing proof of your identity in the form of an
identity document, it is advisable to use the KopieID App to make a secure copy of the document.
This is an app created by the government that allows you to add a watermark to the copy of your
identity document and to delete data that are not required. UM requires you, at the very least, to
render your BSN number and passport photo and the so-called Machine Readable Zone at the
bottom of the document illegible.
Charges for exercising your rights

Exercising your rights under the new privacy legislation is free of charge. If you request additional
copies, however, UM may charge you an administrative fee. You will be advised of this in advance.
If your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if you repeatedly submit a
request, UM may charge an administrative fee for processing your request or refuse to accept the
request. You will be advised of this in writing.
Right of access
You have the right to know whether your personal data are being processed by UM. If they are,
you also have the right to know what data are being processed, for what purpose, whether and
with whom they are being shared and how long they will be kept.
Right to rectification
If the personal data relating to you that UM is processing are found to be incorrect, you have the
right to have these data corrected. If the personal data relating to you that UM is processing are
found to be incomplete, you have the right to have these data completed.
Right to erasure
You have the right to have personal data relating to you that UM is processing erased, but only in
the following circumstances:
    Your personal data are no longer necessary for the purpose for which they were being
     processed.
    You have withdrawn your consent and UM has no other lawful basis for continuing to process
     your personal data.
    You have objected to the processing and UM has no compelling legitimate grounds for
     continuing to process your personal data.
    It has been proven that your personal data have been processed unlawfully.
    UM has a legal obligation to erase your personal data.
You do not have the right to erasure in the following circumstances:
    The processing of your personal data are necessary to exercise the right of freedom of
     expression and information.
    UM has to process your personal data in the context of a legal obligation and/or a task carried
     out in the public interest.
    The processing of your personal data is necessary for public health purposes in the public
     interest.
    The processing of your personal data is necessary for archiving purposes in the public interest,
     scientific research or statistical purposes, and erasure of the data is likely to render impossible
     or seriously impair the achievement of these purposes.
    UM requires your personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.
Right to restrict processing
You have the right to stop UM from processing your personal data (temporarily), without it being
deleted. You only have this right in the following circumstances:
    You contest the accuracy of the personal data processed by UM.
    Your data have been processed unlawfully, but you do not want the data to be deleted.
    UM no longer needs your personal data, but you need it in order to establish, exercise or
     defend a legal claim.
    You have objected to the processing of your personal data by UM and are waiting for UM’s
     response.
If processing is restricted, your personal data will continue to be stored by UM. UM will only
process personal data in respect of which processing has been restricted:
    with your consent;
    to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim;
    to protect another person’s rights;
    for reasons of important public interest.

Right to data portability
If personal data are processed on the basis of your consent or for the performance of a contract,
you have the right to have these personal data transferred to a third party. The processing must be
digital. In addition, transfer of the data must not adversely affect the rights of others.
Right to object
If UM processes your personal data on the basis of a task carried out in the public interest or on
the basis of its legitimate interests, you can object to this. UM will then weigh up the various
interests once again. If, having weighed up all the interests involved, UM believes that it has
compelling legitimate grounds for continuing to process your personal data, your objection will be
rejected. The same applies if your personal data are necessary for the establishment, exercise or
defence of a legal claim.
Rights related to automated individual decision-making, including profiling
In principle, UM does not make decisions based solely on automated individual decision-making,
including profiling. An exception to this is the automatic blocking of ICT facilities where the
integrity and security of these facilities is at stake. In this event, UM will endeavour to reach a
solution with you as quickly as possible.
Right to withdraw your consent
If your personal data are processed on the basis of your consent, you can withdraw this consent at
any time. The withdrawal of your consent does not have retroactive effect.
Complaints
If you have a complaint about the way UM processes your personal data, please contact UM using
the contact details below.
Maastricht University
attn. Data Protection Officer
Postbus 616
6200 MD Maastricht
privacy@maastrichtuniversity.nl
You can also contact UM’s Data Protection Officer directly by emailing fg@maastrichtuniversity.nl.
Additionally, you can submit a complaint to the Dutch Data Protection Authority. Details of how to
do this can be found on the Data Protection Authority’s website.
Changes to this Privacy Statement
This privacy statement will be revised from time to time to ensure that it remains up to date. In
the event of major changes, you will be notified.
Start tekst
